Asian Art and Architecture Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Asian Art and Architecture Slide Collection
0000-2000
VRC 703
Yale University Arts Library
5
21 boxes, 4 containers
Collection of 2,051 slides of painting, sculpture, architecture, and decorative arts, from Cambodia, Indonesia, India, Japan, Laos, Myanmar, Sri Lanka, Thailand, and Vietnam requested by Professor Mimi Hall Yiengpruksawan ca. 2000-2005. Some basic identifying information given in English on slide mounts or guide cards.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection of 2,051 slides of painting, sculpture, architecture, and decorative arts, from Cambodia, Indonesia, India, Japan, Laos, Myanmar, Sri Lanka, Thailand, and Vietnam requested by Professor Mimi Hall Yiengpruksawan ca. 2000-2005. Some basic identifying information given in English on slide mounts or guide cards.
Arrangement
Organized by region (East Asia, South and Southeast Asia) and further subdivided by country and then medium.
Arts, Asian; Slides; Reproductions
- Asia (Box 1)
  - Maps (26 slides) [Slide box 1] (Box 1)
- East Asia (Box 1)
  - Japan (Box 1)
    - Painting (Box 1)
      - General (Box 1)
        - Technical (16 slides) (Box 1)
        - Mandalas (17 slides) (Box 1)
        - Buddhist Painting (75 slides) [Slide boxes 1-2] (Box 1)
          - Zen Painting (20 slides) [Slide box 2] (Box 1)
          - Zen Portraits (10 slides) (Box 1)
          - Collateral Zen images (16 slides) (Box 1)
      - Heian period [Slide box 3] (Box 1)
        - Various (44 slides) (Box 1)
        - Genji (6 slides) (Box 1)
      - Kamakura period (Box 1)
        - Various (78 slides) [Slide boxes 3-4] (Box 1)
      - Muromachi period [Slide box 4-5] (Box 1)
        - Various (103 slides) (Box 1)
      - Momoyama period [Slide box 5] (Box 1)
        - Various (78 slides) (Box 1)
      - Edo period [Slide box 6] (Box 2)
        - Various (111 slides) (Box 2)
      - 19th - 20th century [Slide box 7-8] (Box 2)
        - Various (117 slides) (Box 2)
    - Architecture [Slide box 8] (Box 2)
      - General Views (43 slides) (Box 2)
      - Tea Ceremony (17 slides) (Box 2)
      - Tea Ceremony (Cont.) (60 slides) [Slide box 9] (Box 2)
      - Capitals and Palaces (12 slides) (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous Locations (30 slides) (Box 2)
      - By Location [Slide box 10] (Box 2)
        - Kyoto (98 slides) (Box 2)
        - Tokyo (7 slides) (Box 2)
    - Ceramics [Slide boxes 10-11] (Box 2)
      - Various (27 slides) (Box 2)
    - Decorative arts (Lacquer, Furniture) (4 slides) [Slide box 11] (Box 2)
    - Metalwork (14 slides) (Box 2)
    - Textiles (7 slides) (Box 2)
    - Sculpture (Box 2)
      - By period (Box 2)
        - Jomon period (11slides) (Box 2)
        - Yayoi period (5 slides) (Box 2)
        - Kofun period (2 slides) (Box 2)
        - Asuka period (22 slides) (Box 2)
        - Nara period (24 slides) (Box 2)
        - Heian period (61 slides) [Slide box 12] (Box 3)
        - Kamakura period (9 slides) (Box 3)
      - Heaven & Hell (24 slides) (Box 3)
      - Various (74 slides) [Slide boxes 12-13] (Box 3)
  - Korea [Slide box 13] (Box 3)
    - Ceramics (Box 3)
      - Various (13 slides) (Box 3)
    - Painting (Box 3)
      - Various (15 slides) (Box 3)
    - Sculpture (Box 3)
      - Various (3 slides) (Box 3)
- South and Southeast Asia (Box 3)
  General
  [Slide box 14]
  - Various (Box 3)
    - By source (Box 3)
      - Kam, Ramayana in the Arts of Asia, 2000 (27 slides) (Box 3)
      - Kerlogue, Arts of Southeast Asia, 2004 (4 slides) (Box 3)
      - World of Buddha (?) (22 slides) (Box 3)
      - Buddha, the Living Way, 1998 (4 slides) (Box 3)
    - Decorative arts (11 slides) [Slide box 15] (Box 3)
    - Sculpture (43 slides) (Box 3)
  - By country (Box 3)
    - Burma (Myanmar) (Box 3)
      - Architecture and Sculpture (Box 3)
        - Various (34 slides) (Box 3)
        - By source (Box 3)
          - Shwedagon (?) (18 slides) (Box 3)
          - Burma Art & Architecture (?) (13 slides) (Box 3)
    - Cambodia [Slide box 16] (Box 3)
      - Architecture and Sculpture (Box 3)
        - Khmer (Box 3)
          - Various (15 slides) (Box 3)
          - By source (Box 3)
            - Garnier, Khmer Art in Reserve, 1997 (16 slides) (Box 3)
          - Angkor (Box 3)
            - Various (11 slides) (Box 3)
            - Angkor Wat (5 slides) (Box 3)
            - Angkor Thom (15 slides) (Box 3)
            - Banteay Srei (17 slides) (Box 3)
          - Cham (31 slides) [Slide box 16-17] (Box 3–4)
          - Preah Vihear (18 slides) (Box 4)
          - Various, by source (Box 4)
            - Guillon, Musée de Sculpture Cam de Dà Nang, 2001 (5 slides) (Box 4)
            - Insider's Vietnam, Laos, and Cambodia (2 slides) (Box 4)
    - Indonesia (Box 4)
      - Decorative and performing arts (Box 4)
        - Jessup, Court Arts of Indonesia, 1990 (26 slides) (Box 4)
      - Architecture and Sculpture (Box 4)
        - Java (Box 4)
          - Borobodur (33 slides) (Box 4)
          - Various (74 slides) [Slide box 18] (Box 4)
        - By source (Box 4)
          - Arts of Indonesia (?) (8 slides) (Box 4)
    - India (Box 4)
      - Architecture and Sculpture (Box 4)
        - Ajanta (55 slides) [Slide boxes 18-19] (Box 4)
        - Bharhut (8 slides) [Slide box 19] (Box 4)
        - Cola (6 slides) (Box 4)
        - Ellora (7 slides) (Box 4)
        - Gandhara (21 slides) (Box 4)
        - Indus (6 slides) (Box 4)
        - Konarak (8 slides) (Box 4)
        - Madurai (10 slides) (Box 4)
        - Mathura (4 slides) [Slide box 20] (Box 4)
        - Mughal (19 slides) (Box 4)
        - Sarnatu (1 slide) (Box 4)
    - Sri Lanka (Box 4)
      - Architecture and Sculpture (Box 4)
        - Various (4 slides) (Box 4)
    - Thailand (Box 4)
      - Architecture and Sculpture (Box 4)
        - Ayutthaya (20 slides) (Box 4)
        - Bangkok (38 slides) (Box 4)
        - Ban Chiang (21 slides) (Box 4)
        - Sukhothai (26 slides) [Slide box 21] (Box 4)
        - By source (Box 4)
        - Sacred Sculpture of Thailand, 1997 (8 slides) (Box 4)
    - Vietnam (Box 4)
      - Architecture and Sculpture (Box 4)
        - By source (Box 4)
          - Guillon, Hindu Buddhist Art of Vietnam, 2001 (29 slides) (Box 4)
          - Rediscovering Vietnam, 1997 (4 slides) (Box 4)
          - Prasart Museum: Treasures of Thailand, 1990 (?) (17 slides) (Box 4)